Sheet music collection on medical themes
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
- Individual songs in English by title, 1.
  - Ocean Honeymoon (Box 5)
    Words by Roger Lewis, music by James White. Chicago: Will Rossiter, c. 1914. On sea sickness on an ocean liner. Sung by the Dolce Sisters.
  - Off I Went to the Doctor (Fragson's Doctor Song)
    Words by Worton David, music by H. Fragson. London: Von Tilzer Music Co. Ltd., c. 1912. Sung by H. Fragson. He goes to various doctors who give him conflicting diagnoses.
  - Oh Alma Mater: Philadelphia College of Pharmacy and Science
    Words by J. W. Sturmer, music by Arno Viehoever. Copyright 1924 by J. W. Sturmer and Arno Viehover. "To the students of the Philadelphia College of Pharmacy and Science."
  - Oh Dear Such Horrid Colds!
    Words by Willis N. Bugbee, music by Thos. B. Weaver. Syracuse, N.Y.: The Willis N. Bugbee Co., 1923. "An Action Song for Children."
  - Oh Doctor
    By Billy Joyce and Rubey Cowan. New York: (Mack) Stark & (Rubey) Cowan Inc., c.1920. On the doctor as a source of alcohol during Prohibition.
  - Oh Doctor!
    Words by Anne Caldwell, music by Harry Tierney. New York: T.B. Harms and Francis, Day & Hunter, c. 1918. From "The Canary" by Harry B. Smith.
  - Oh! Doctor, Doctor
    Words by Cyrus Wood, music by Sigmund Romberg. New York: Shapiro, Bernstein & Co., c. 1918. From the musical comedy, "The Melting of Molly."
  - Oh Doctor, That Did It
    Words by W. Frank Brown, music by Harold Potter. Keokuk, Iowa: Dr. Billie Song Shoppe. Copyright 1946 by W. Frank Brown, Keokuk, Iowa. Sung by Marian Morgan. The doctor as object of love.
  - Oh Gee - Poor Me Never-No-More
    Words and music by Thos. S. Allen. Boston: Thos. S. Allen, c. 1908. On a hangover.
  - Oh God Hear Their Cry!
    Words by Mrs. Clara Richie, music by J. P. Webster, adapted by Clara Richie. Cleveland: S. Brainard's Sons, c. 1878. "A beautiful song suggested by the terrible yellow fever sufferings in the south."
  - Oh! Frenchy
    Words by Sam Ehrlich, music by Con Conrad. New York: Broadway Music Corporation, c. 1918. An American nurse in France meets a soldier from Paris in World War I. See followup song above, "Frenchy, Come to Yankee Land."
  - Oh My My
    Words and music by Vini Poncia and Richard Starkey. Copyright 1973 by Braintree Music Inc., c/o Mitchell, Silberberg & Knupp, Los Angeles, 1973. Rights for the United Kingdom and Ireland controlled by Rondor Music (London) Limited. Recorded by Ringo Starr on Apple Records. The doctor tells him to boogie woogie.
  - Oh! My Operation
    Words by Billy Rose and Ballard MacDonald, music by Jesse Greer. New York: Jerome H. Remick & Co., c. 1927. Jane Mac Pherson has had an appendectomy and now resists advances by men. Sung by the Landry Sisters.
  - Oh! Say! Doctor! (He Falls for the Ladies Every Time)
    Words by Arthur J. Lamb, music by Alfred Solman. New York: Jos. W. Stern & Co., c. 1909. Mrs. Brown consults the doctor about her husband.
  - Oh, Susie, Behave
    Words by Ed Rose, music by Abe Olman. New York: McCarthy & Fisher Inc., c. 1918. Susie is a nurse in World War I.
  - Oil on the Brain
    Words and music by Eastburn. Philadelphia: J. Marsh, c. 1864. "Comic ballad" about the oil craze with a verse about medicine. "To the Afflicted."
  - Oil on the Brain
    Words and music by Eastburn. Philadelphia: J. Marsh, c. 1865. Another version of the above.
  - Oil on the Brain
    Broadside with the words of "Oil on the Brain." New York: H. De Marsan, Publisher, n.d. (19th cent.). "As sung in New-York, Philadelphia, and all the principal cities of the Union, where the île fever abounds."
  - The Old Commodore
    Trimmed 18th century broadside or hand-colored print containing words but no music. "The Words by Mr. Lonsdale." "Sung with unbounded applause by Mr. Taylor, of Theatre Royal, Covent Garden." The Commodore suffers from gout.
  - Old Doctor Brown
    Words by Earl Jones, music by Herbert Ingraham. New York: Shapiro, c. 1910. Comic verses on Dr. Brown's patients.
  - Old-Time Remedies, or Goose Grease and Boneset Tea
    By J. B. Herbert. Cincinnati: Fillmore Music House, c. 1903.
  - One and One is One
    By John Fiddler. London: B. Feldman & Co., Ltd./Biscuit Music, c. 1973. Recorded by Medicine-Head. Image of drugs on the cover. Song content is not medical
  - One of his Legs is Longer than it Really Ought to Be
    Words and music by Lew Dockstader. New York: Spaulding & Gray. Copyright 1893 by Spaulding & Kornder. Sung by Lew Dockstader. The doctor set a broken leg leaving one leg longer than the other.
  - Oo! Doctor
    Words by Donovan Parsons, music by Tony Castle. London: Cecil Lennox & Co., c. 1923. "Comedy Song One-Step." Mabel is attracted to the doctor down the street.
  - Ophelia Pulse M.D. (The Lady Doctor)
    Words and music by Lawrence Hanray. London: Reynolds & Co., n.d. (turn of 20th cent.). "Humorous Song." Sung by Lawrence Hanray.
  - Ould Doctor Ma' Ginn
    Words by Arthur Stringer, music by Hermann Löhr. London: Chappell & Co., Ltd, c. 1909. From "Songs in Exile." Sung by Kennerley Rumford.
  - Our America's Nurse
    Words and music by Evelyn Adams. Portland, Oregon: Westmore Music Corporation, c. 1943. Note in pen that copyright was reassigned to the composer. In praise of World War II nurses. Sung by Nora Lou.
  - Our Family Doctor, or The Rise of a Butcher Boy
    By J. S. Fearis. Chicago: A. Beirly, c. 1894. A young man with no medical training becomes a doctor for the sake of a young woman and her family.
  - Our Surgeon General March
    Composed by Samuel J. J. Kelly. Philadelphia: M. D. Swisher. Copyright 1899 by Samuel J. J. Kelly. "To the Surgeon General of Penna." Photograph on cover of Surgeon General John V. Shoemaker.
  - "Oyea!"
    Words by G. Hubi-Newcombe, music by Charles A. True. London: Charles Woolhouse, n.d. (turn of 20th cent.). Cover shows a young woman selling trinkets. The song refers to "a balm for every healing."
  - Panacea
    Words and music by Leonard Feather and Ralph Burns. New York: Charling Music Corp., c. 1946. Panacea refers to a woman.
  - The Patient Sleeps
    Words by William Ernest Henley, music by Theodore Chanler. New York: G. Schirmer, Inc., c. 1949. On the experience of receiving anesthesia.
  - Pat's Water-Cure Criticism
    Words by Charles Follen Adams, music by Howard M. Dow. Boston: White, Smith & Co., c. 1879. "Written expressly for and sung by Mr. H. C. Barnabee."
  - P.D.'s Little Brown Jug
    Published by the pharmaceutical company Parke-Davis & Company, ca. 1938. Relates to an award for "Branch Managers' Month."
  - Phew! Them Golden Kippers! Don't They Tid'ly Wink
    Words by Charles Osborne, music by E. W. Eyre. London: Charles Sheard & Co., n.d. (turn of 20th cent.) Last verse refers to calling the doctor. "George Beauchamp's Latest Parody."
  - Physic, Law[?] and Spirits, or the History of the Yorkshire Doctor
    Engraved sheet music. Music adapted by S. Wilkinson. London: Printed by Metzler & Son, n.d. (early 19th century). "New Comic Song as Sung by Mr. Matthews."
  - The Pill
    Words and music by Lorene Allen, Don McHan and T. D. Bayless. Nashville, Tenn.: Coal Miner's Music, Inc. and Guarantee Music, Inc., c. 1973 and 1975. Recorded by Loretta Lynn on MCA Records. On the birth control pill.
  - Pipe-Dream Blues
    Words and music by Spencer Williams, Marguerite Kendall, and J. Russel Robinson. Chicago: Lee S. Roberts, c. 1918. Di Dong, an immigrant from China, smokes opium in his pipe.
  - Pity Sick Otto
    Composed by Eric Steiner. New York: Mills Music, Inc., c. 1954.
  - Poor Thing!
    Words by Harry Hunter, music by Walter Howard. London: Joseph Williams, 1890. Sung by Walter Howard and the Moore & Burgess Minstrels. Illustration of a man in black-face playing the banjo. Comic song about a woman who marries a student at Middlesex Hospital.
  - Pray for Me, O Mother Dear
    By the Sanatorian (Addison D. Crabtre, M.D.) Copyright 1868 by A. D. Crabtre. Published for the author by W. A Pond & Co., New York. From "Songs by the Sanatorian." Advertisement on the back for the Boston Chronic Disease Infirmary, headed by Addison D. Crabtre, M.D., known as "The Sanatorian."
  - Puff (The Magic Dragon)
    Words and music by Peter Yarrow and Leonard Lipton. New York: Pepamar Music Corp., c. 1963. Recorded by Peter, Paul & Mary on Warner Bros. Records.
  - Put a Plaster on My Chest
    Cover only. No music. Words and music by Harry Nicholls. London: Hopwood & Crew, n.d. (turn of 20th cent.). "Burlesque Ballad."
  - Rag-i-ri-tis (You've Got the) (Box 6)
    Words by J. Grant Gibson, music by Fred Hylands. New York: Hylands and Gibson, c. 1913.
  - The Red Cross Nurse
    Words by Frank Dumont, music by Richard P. Lilly. Philadelphia: Dumont Publishing Co., c. 1916. Sung by Billy Sheldon, Dumonts Minstrels.
  - The Rejected Volunteer
    Words by J. Hickory Wood, music by Herbert Schartau. London: Reynolds & Co., n.d. (ca. 1900). A volunteer for the (Boer?) war got rejected four times by the doctor. "Humorous Song." Sung by Herbert Schartau.
  - Remember Nurse Cavell
    Words by Gordon V. Thompson, music by Jules Brazil. Copyright 1915 by Gordon V. Thompson. Published by Thompson Publishing Co., Toronto. On the martyred nurse Edith Cavell. "Songs of the Homeland No. 7."
  - Remember the Nurse
    Words and music by John W. Borradaile. Copyright 1918 by John W. Borradaile, Philadelphia. On World War I nurses.
  - The Rheumatiz: Song for Little Folks
    Words and Music by Bessie M. Alston. Lebanon, Ohio: March Brothers Publishers, c. 1917. Song for children with suggested costumes and motions.
  - The Rheumatiz
    Words and music by Bessie M. Alston. Copyright 1917 by March Brothers. Copyright transferred 1937 to Paine Publishing Co., Publishers, Dayton, Ohio. "Action Songs and Song Novelties." Later version of the previous item.
  - Roll a Little Pill for Me
    Words and music by Norma Gray. New York: M. Witmark & Sons, c. 1911. Sung by Norma Gray of the Gray Trio. On smoking opium.
  - Rose Ann of Charing Cross
    Words by Kermit Goell, music by Mabel Wayne. New York: Shapiro, Bernstein & Co., c. 1942. The singer fell in love with his nurse at Charing Cross Hospital in London. Image of performer Blue Barron on the cover.
  - Rose Ann of Charing Cross
    Words by Kermit Goell, music by Mabel Wayne. New York: Shapiro, Bernstein & Co., c. 1942. See previous item. Image of Russ Morgan on cover.
  - Rose Ann of Charing Cross
    Words by Kermit Goell, music by Mabel Wayne. New York: Shapiro, Bernstein & Co., c. 1942. See first item for this title. Image of Guy Lombardo on cover.
  - The Rose of No Man's Land
    Words by Jack Caddigan, music by James A. Brennan. New York: Leo Feist, Inc., c. 1918. On the Red Cross nurse in World War I.
  - Run for the Doctor
    Words and music by G. W. Hunt, arranged by W. Sim. New York: Frank Harding's Music House, n.d. (turn of 20th cent.?). About the singer's hypochondriac mother-in-law who lives with him. "Popular songs sung by Miss Ella Wesner, the great serio comic artiste."
  - Running a Temperature
    Words by Milton Pascal, music by Edgar Fairchild. New York: Edward B. Maks Music Corporation, c. 1936. A love song. "As played by Clyde Lucas and his California Dons."
  - Rush Medical Students March
    Composed by John G. Meachum, Op. 7, No. 1. Chicago: Henry Detmar Music House, c. 1895. "Dedicated to the Professors and Students of Rush Medical College."
  - The Saint Vitus Rag
    Words by J. Leubrie Hill, music by J. Rosamund Johnson. New York: Jerome H. Remick & Company, c. 1912. Sung by Johnson and Hart.
  - Save Our Little Nell
    Words by W. Murdoch Lind, music by Homer Tourjée. New York: Homer Tourjée Music Publishing Co., 1896. Image of Luke Fildes, "The Doctor," on the cover.
  - Say that I Died for My Country's Sake
    Words by Caspar Nathan, music by F. Henri Klickman. Chicago: Frank K. Root & Co., c, 1914. Cover image of a dying soldier in World War I and a Red Cross nurse.
  - Scarlet-Fever Jane (Oh Jane, Oh Jane, My Pretty Jane)
    Cover only. No music. By G. W. Hunter. London: Francis Bros. & Day, n.d. (19th cent.). "Eccentric Parody on 'Scotch Lassie Jean'."
  - The Seasick Sailor
    Words by Harold Adamson, music by Jimmy McHugh. New York: Robbins Music Corporation, c. 1943. "From the RKO Radio Picture 'Around the World'." Performed by Kay Kyser's Band.
  - She was an Angel of Mercy
    Words by George Bert and Chas. Britton, music by Lawrence Wright. London: The Lawrence Wright Music Co., c. 1915. "A Tribute to the Memory of Nurse [Edith] Cavell."
  - She'll Be There
    Words by Jack Caddigan, music by James A. Brennan. Boston: Daly Music Publisher, Inc., c.1917. "A Tribute to American Womenhood." Shows a nurse on the cover but the lyrics are about women's other contributions to World War I.
  - She's a Patient of Mine
    Words and music by Chris Smith. Chicago: Victor Kremer Music Publisher, c. 1910. From "Frazee and Leder's Grand Production 'Jumping Jupiter' by Will Philbrick." The doctor tells his wife that the pretty maiden is his patient.
  - She's Just What the Doctor Ordered
    Words and music by Fred Rose. San Francisco: Villa Morét, c. 1927.
  - The Soldier's Last Request
    Words by Harry Graves, music by Arthur M. Cohen and John Martin. Erie, Pennsylvania: Brehm Bros., c. 1915. Cover image of a dying soldier and Red Cross nurse
  - Some Little Bug is Going to Find You (Food Song)
    Words by Benjamin Hapgood Burt and Roy Atwell, music by Silvio Hein. New York: T. B. Harms and Francis, Day & Hunter, c. 1915. On germs in food and water. Sung by Roy Atwell in Franz Lehar's operetta "Alone At Last."
  - Somewhere in France is the Lily
    Words by Philander Johnson, music by Joseph E. Howard. New York: M. Witmark & Sons, c. 1917. World War I song. Sung by Joseph E. Howard. On the "flower of youth" fighting in France.
  - Song of the Army Nurse Corps: The Official Anthem of the Army Nurse Corps
    Words by Hy Zaret, music by Lou Singer. New York: Leeds Music Corporation, c. 1944. World War II nursing.
  - Sontag Polka
    Arranged by Chas. d'Albert. Boston: Oliver Ditson, n.d. (19th cent.). "Elisir d'Amore." "Madam Sontag as Adina; Sigr. Lablache as Dr. Dulcarno."
  - A Spoonful of Sugar
    Words and music by Richard M. Sherman and Robert B. Sherman. Buena Vista, California: Wonderland Music Company, c. 1963. From Walt Disney's "Mary Poppins" starring Julie Andrews and Dick van Dyke. "A spoonful of sugar makes the medicine go down."
  - St. Elsewhere
    Composed by Dave Gruson. Mimsey Music and Roaring Fork Music, c. 1982. From the MTM Enterprises television series, "St. Elsewhere" (a hospital).
  - Steam Pills: Dr. Morisson & Mynheer Von Shlop
    Possibly a later version of the next entry. Words by T. Prest. Philadelphia: Hot.[?] Meignen & Co., n.d. (19th cent.). Mynheer Von Shlop, who is only three feet tall, takes Dr. Morisson's steam pills and grows. Spoof on medical quackery.
  - Steam Pills: Dr. Puffison and Meynheer Von Shlop
    Cover and first page of music only. Words by T. Prest, music by Willm. Taylor. London: George & Manby, n.d. (early 19th cent.). Mynheer Von Shlop, rejected by the ladies because he is only three feet tall, takes Dr. Puffison's patent steam pills and grows. The music appears complete. For the remaining verses, see previous item.
  - Stopping the Hiccoughs
    By Edna Mae Burnham. St. Louis, Missouri: Shattinger Piano & Music Co., c. 1946. A boy has the hiccoughs.
  - Strictly Germ-Proof (The Antiseptic Baby)
    Words by Arthur Guiterman, music by John Sacco. New York: G. Schirmer, c. 1941.
  - Summer Green, Autumn Gold
    Words by Paul Francis Weber, music by Maurice Jarre. New York: Famous Music Corporation, c. 1973. From the Paramount Pictures film, "Ash Wednesday," starring Elizabeth Taylor. The song is about growing older and has no medical content, but the cover image is labeled "Barbara Sawyer and her beauticians" and shows an operation for a facelift.
  - Testimonials (Box 7)
    Words and music by Harry Castling. London: Charles Sheard & Co. Copyright 1902 in USA. Comic song on patent medicines. "Sung by The Blinker, George Brooks."
  - That Epidemic Rag
    Words by Billy Foran, music by Edna Williams. London: B. Feldman & Co., n.d. Copyright in USA by Jos. Stern & Co., New York, n.d. (ca. 1910). Sung by Lionel Mackinder in the Empire Revue "All the Winners." Reference to germs.
  - That Red Cross Girl of Mine
    Words and music by E. C. Cannon. Columbus, Ohio: Buckeye Music, c. 1917. Red Cross nurses in World War I.
  - That Red Cross Girl of Mine
    Words and music by Ed. C. Cannon. Columbus, Ohio: Buckeye Music Pub. Co., c. 1917. Variant of previous item.
  - That Sneezing Song
    Words by James Clarence Harvey, music by Arthur Nevin. New York: Edward Schuberth & Co., c. 1900. Sung by Maurice Farkoa.
  - That's the Doctor, Bill
    Words by Henry S. Creamer, music by Silvio Hein. Copyright 1909 by Marie Cahill Music Co. Published in the World Magazine, Sunday, September 26, 1909. A woman excuses herself to a suitor who finds her holding another a man's hand by saying "That's the Doctor, Bill." Sung by Marie Cahill in "The Boys and Betty."
  - That's Why You're Dancing Tonight
    Words by George Reed and Ray Smith, music by Alice Lucey Reed. Copyright applied for March 5, 1938, New Jersey Elks Association, by their agent, Howard S. Lewis, Burlington, New Jersey. Song appears to be for a benefit dance in aid of "crippled" children. "Dedicated to crippled children everywhere."
  - There is Beauty
    Words by Rosa Emma Collins, music by Charles Salaman. London: J. B. Cramer & Co., n.d. (19th cent.). "The copyright of this song has been presented by the composer to the Health Resort Fund of the Central London Throat & Ear Hospital." Image of the hospital on back cover and list of five songs for which copyright was presented as a gift to the Health Resort Fund.
  - There isn't Anything that Can't be Cured
    Words by Vincent Bryan, music by Harry Bulger. New York: Jerome H. Remick & Co., c. 1906. From Henry W. Savage's production, "The Man from Now," starring Harry Bulger.
  - There's an Angel Missing from Heaven: She'll be Found Somewhere Over There
    Words by Paul B. Armstrong, music by Robert Speroy. Chicago: Frank K. Root & Co., c. 1918. "Dedicated to the American Red Cross." Red Cross nursing in World War I.
  - There's Nothing Like Jolly Good Health, Hear, Hear!
    Words by R. P. Weston and Bert Lee, music by Harris Weston. London: Francis, Day & Hunter, c. 1930. A drinking song.
  - Thermogene: Burlesque Ballad
    Words and music by R. P. Weston and Burt Lee. London: Francis, Day & Hunter Ltd., c. 1925. Sung by Nixon Grey. Thermogenes were medicated heat pads.
  - They've Got Me Doin' It Now
    Words and music by Irving Berlin. New York: Waterson, Berlin & Snyder Co., c. 1913. He calls for the doctor because he can't stop dancing.
  - They've Got Me Doin' It Now Medley
    Words and music by Irving Berlin. New York: Waterson, Berlin & Snyder Co., c. 1913. Possibly later version of the previous song.
  - A Thousand a Year - And the Liver Complaint
    Cover only. No music. Words by Harry Hunter, music by E. Forman. London, Francis Bros. & Day, n.d. (late 19th cent.). Sung by Walter Howard of the Mohawk Minstrels. Illustration of a man in blackface and large feet playing the banjo.
  - The Thyroid Gland
    Words and music by R. P. Weston and Bert Lee. London: Francis, Day & Hunter, c. 1921. Sung by Lake and Barrasford. On rejuvenation via gland therapy.
  - The Times Are Hard
    Cover only, no music. Words and music by Robert Baker. London: Monro and May, n.d. (mid-19th cent.). Sung by Mr. Fitzwilliam and others. Engraved cover shows a crowd before a "Drug Market."
  - To a Surgeon
    Words by Roselle Mercier Montgomery, music by George B. Nevin. Boston: Oliver Ditson Company, c. 1926. Praise to the surgeon who saves lives.
  - To the Hospital Nurses in Every Clime
    Words by Friendship Gloucester, music by Franz Hoffman. Washington, D.C.: The H. Kirkus Dugdale Co., c. 1913. On Red Cross nursing.
  - Tom Kelson
    By J. Beuler. Sung by Mr. Fitzwilliam with accompaniment by J. Clinton. London: J. Beuler, n.d. (early-mid 19th cent.). "Improved Edition." Comic song about a sailor who has had all his limbs amputated by a surgeon after he was injured in a naval battle.
  - Tommy's Guardian Angel, or What is Nurse to Do!
    Words by Adrian Ross, music by Augustus Barratt. London: E. Ascherberg & Co., c. 1900. Red Cross nursing.
  - Touching That Little Affair
    Words and music by Bennett Scott and C. G. Cotes. London: Howard & Co. Copyright 1898 in the USA. Sung by George Robey. Comic song partly about a "lady doctor."
  - The Troubles of a Troubadour
    Words by Vivian Grahame, music by Fredc. Scarsbrook. London: Willey & Co., n.d. (19th cent.). Comic song in which the troubador is beaten by the baron's "varlets" and suffers from a cold and bruises.
  - Try a Kiss on your Patient
    Words and music by Emma R. Hicks. Copyright 1944 by Emma R. Hicks. Published for the composer by C. Howard Lowden, Camden, N.J. The army doctor tells nurses to "try a kiss on your patient." World War II song.
  - Turkey Rhubarb
    One page only. Words to a verse but no music. Words and music by Robert Coombs. London: C. Sheard, n.d. (19th cent.). Sung by George Leybourne. About a patent medicine sold by a Turk.
  - Twigg's "Family Doctor"
    Words by Leslie Wood and Walter Dowling, music by Walter Dowling. London: Reynolds & Co., c. 1909. Sung by Walter Dowling in the "Fantastics' Entertainment." Timothy Twigg, with no medical training, writes a health booklet to make money.
  - Two-Lipped Salve
    Words by Bert Kalmar, music by Harry Puck. New York: Kalmar & Puck Music Co., c. 1913. Sung by May Irwin in "Widow by Proxy."
  - Under the Banner of the Red Cross Nurse
    Words and music by Eugene Quaw. New York: National Publishing Co., c. 1917. "Dedicated to the Red Cross of America." On Red Cross nurses in World War I.
  - Valse de l'Hopital: In Aid of the Funds of the Devon and Exeter Hospital
    Composed by E. Carpentier De Selvier. Exeter: Published by the author, n.d. (19th cent.). "The profit derived from these waltzes is for the benefit of Devon & Exeter Hospital."
  - Vitamins Plus
    Words by Gertrude Gore, music by Olive Dungan. New York: G. Ricordi & Co., c. 1952. From "Eight Character Studies for Young Folks." Song for children on eating healthy foods.
  - Water Cure Polka
    Composed by Ch. Schuster. Boston: Oliver Ditson, n.d. (mid 19th cent.). "Composed and respectfully dedicated to Drs. Wesselhoeft & Felerer."
  - We Haven't Spoken Since
    Words by A. J. Mills, music by Bennett Scott. London: B. Feldman, n.d. (19th cent.). Sung by George Robey. Humorous song with one verse on medicine.
  - We've Got the Mumps
    Words by Willis N. Bugbee, music by Thos. B. Weaver. Syracuse, N.Y.: The Willis N. Bugbee Co., c. 1920. A song for children to sing. Includes motions to be made by the children.
  - We've Had a Lovely Time, So Long, Good Bye
    Words by Blanche Merrill, music by Leo Edwards. New York: Chas. K. Harris, c. 1912. From "The Trained Nurses." This song doesn't have medical content.
  - What the Doctor Ordered (Or Everything Done Browne): Humorous Ballad on the New Food Regulations
    Words an music by Sylvester Gaffney. Dublin: Walton's Piano and Musical Instrument Galleries, c. 1951. On the nuisances of complying with the new food handling regulations.
  - When a Man's a Little Bit Poorly
    Words by T. Hudson, music by J. Blewitt. London: T. E. Pudy, n.d. (early to mid 19th cent.). The doctor's successive treatments make him feel worse; he gets better when he gives up all "physic."
  - When Santa Had the Rheumatiz